hi and welcome back to the channel today
we're going to do the poll winning ice
cream of Japanese Apple so if you want
to see why I put that up and how I made
it stick around and I'll show you
[Music]
so my wife and I were lucky enough to go
to Japan for our honeymoon along with
the Philippines but we went to Tokyo we
stayed in Shinjuku and it was amazing
the holiday itself was just you know a
once in a lifetime kind of opportunity
and we were walking around Shibuya
actually and it was this uh a small
little ice cream Cellar in a cart really
old-fashioned
but he had some really unique flavors
and one of them was just
Apple miso and I really wanted to try it
so it was boiling hot that day we went
there
got some scooped up and it was
astonishing really really good it had
this completely unique kind of flavor
and texture to it something like I'd
never had before and I really wanted to
try it so
it's been a while you know a few years
since since our honeymoon
and I thought it'd be a great
opportunity to remember that amazing
holiday and make some of that ice cream
myself
I tried to find some Fuji apples
it's not easy to get that kind of thing
over here in England so I went with the
closest thing that was available
color wise they're pretty close I think
Fuji apples are a little bit sweeter
than these These are Pink Ladies but
they would do the job absolutely fine
and along with that we're gonna use
some white miso paste which is basically
a flavor enhancer but with notes of
kind of Sesame and uh it's a kind of
warm flavor it's really difficult to oh
it's Umami so let's just get stuck into
it and talk about how I made this ice
cream
so the first thing we did was take our
apples we want to get 200 grams of Apple
here chop them up into nice little cubes
and put them into a pan along with 100
grams of sugar and 50 grams of water
you're going to heat this up in the pan
for quite a while it takes about half an
hour 45 minutes until the Apple breaks
down really nice and soft and then
you're going to add in your miso paste
so I've added just over 13 grams of the
miso paste here stir that in nicely make
sure that's all completely warmed and
Incorporated and then you're going to
just let that cool down for a few hours
once it's completely cooled down you're
going to put it in your blender and go
to town you're going to really Blitz
this within an inch of its life you want
it as smooth as you can possibly get it
you want it really smooth but you don't
want to take all the texture of that
Apple out you want to just leave some of
those fibers free
once it's all completely Blended pop it
in a container and we're going to
prepare our ice cream base for this
you're going to start with your milk
and then add in all of your Apple puree
finally the remaining sugar and your
milk powder get it all nicely combined
to make sure everything's emulsified
then you're gonna
see here actually that the base split
now I wasn't expecting this to happen
which was quite unusual so what I did
here was take a small teaspoon of sugar
and a quarter teaspoon of sunflower
lesser thin
mix the sugar and list them together and
then added that back into the split base
turn the heat off
and then just gently combine it whisking
it slowly and then as you can see the
base started to come back together this
is a really good way to rescue an ice
cream base that is curdled
this won't work if you've done an egg
base as you're going to have the lumps
of egg all through your ice cream but
here as we've got an eggless it's not a
problem we've managed to save this ice
cream
once your base is finished you're going
to put it in the fridge to completely
chill I left this in overnight and then
take it out one final stir because you
really are going to see an unusual base
consistency here all those apple fibers
are going to swell overnight which is
exactly what you want pop it in your ice
cream machine and churn this will look
unusual to churn but that is perfectly
normal with this ice cream I promise you
it will turn out perfect at the end
when it's finished put it in your
containers pop it in the freezer to
completely harden off
[Music]
it's been a few days since the ice cream
was made we're going to get some scooped
up into a bowl and see what it turned
out like
[Music]
scooped really nicely you can see the
little flecks of Apple flesh in there
and that's something that we really
wanted to recreate based on the one that
we tried a couple of things the Lesser
thin
ignore the brand
um that's the important part for
bringing this base back together
if you struggle and have made a
fruit-based ice cream and it has split
while you're heating it or cooking it on
the hob you run a really good chance of
getting it back with that as long as
it's not egg-based like I said if you
use eggs and it splits and curdles
you're not going to do anything with it
because you're going to have lumps of
egg in there but what you could do is
strain those bits of egg out and then
treat the base with less than to bring
it all back together that is another
possibility we'll talk about that in
another video let's try some of this ice
cream and see how it turned out
[Music]
it's so different to other ice creams
it's almost like a one-off it's a it's a
very unique thing this
and that's we we spoke about it when we
actually had it in Tokyo and it's
you get
the aftertaste of Apple but you get this
warming kind of toasted
flavor to it that comes from this miso
it was I mean it's just made
from soybeans and water with a bit of
salt in there but when you smell it
smells malty and that's something that
we we spoke about the other night is
when you compare it to
malt extract there's some real
similarities there so there's obviously
some flavor noise to interact together
to create that same kind of flavor and
that is what it does for your ice cream
it's really
it's really good you know it's the first
time I've used miso and ice cream and
and it probably won't be the last
what's really nice though is you get
those little bits of Apple
on your palette in your in your teeth on
your tongue as you're eating it it
creates a a multi-faceted kind of thing
when you're eating it a lot of ice cream
just melts but this one when as you eat
it you can taste it you've got a
textural thing you can bite onto that
also has that flavor as well so it's
it's really unique and it's Unique in a
great way so if you want to try an ice
cream that is different apple flavored
you could probably get a different
flavor based on the type of apple that
you use but I really recommend trying
this one it's a very special thing from
Japan on our honeymoon I hope you do try
this one let us know if you do and what
you think of it
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe and we'll
see you next time
[Music]